<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hardware | Tonni Das Jui</title><link>/tag/hardware/</link><atom:link href="/tag/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Hardware</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/media/icon_hueab7d6d199de416be2b9f9dfddb82a1a_48284_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Hardware</title><link>/tag/hardware/</link></image><item><title>Wireless Notice Board</title><link>/project/wireless-notice-board/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/wireless-notice-board/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="why-i-have-done-it">Why I have done it:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>For my Digital System Design course in my undergraduate program at BRAC University, I came up with the idea of this project.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="when-i-have-done-it">When I have done it:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I have done it while I was in my 4rt year of undergraduate program at BRAC University, Bangladesh.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="technical-details">Technical details:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>GSM module, Arduino mega, LED display, C language etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="description">Description:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>It Can show msg that is sent from a mobile number which is coded in the machine and can receive msg while anyone presses the button.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It is a wireless device that allows sending and receiving massages from/to a phone and display received massages on the display of the device.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It is used for updating students about information’s by faculty if the faculty is not at the office when the students come to visit him.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The student can press the button to send a notification to the faculty and when the faculty sees it in his phone he can reply the msg and the msg should be shown on the led screen.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Color Sorter</title><link>/project/color-sorter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/color-sorter/</guid><description>&lt;p>Color sorting machine can sort out different objects and place it in it&amp;rsquo;s bucket according to different colors.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="why-i-have-done-it">Why I have done it:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I built this out of self interest. This was my first website building project.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="when-i-have-done-it">When I have done it:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>After I completed graduating from BRAC University, Bangladesh.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="technical-details">Technical details:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I used C programming language, Energia IDE, MSP430, motor sensor, color sensor.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="description">Description:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>It is a device capable of sorting out items of different color in different places.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It can be used for sorting different colored fruits in the industries.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It has 3 ways for 3 different colors.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Each colored object will fall in that colored way.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Color sensor detects the color of the object.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The motor moves the object according to the ordered angle from &lt;code>MSP430&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>